让我们总结一下本讲座的一些重要思想。我想要的第一件事
Let's summarize some of the big ideas from this lecture. The first thing that I want
要说，我不能说这个强烈，是坐标框架是你的朋友。
to say, and I can't say this strongly enough, is that coordinate frames are your friend.
它们使分解和理解复杂问题变得非常容易。所以我们分配坐标
They make it very easy to decompose and understand complex problems. So we assign coordinate
框架到机器人环境中的所有东西，并写下它之间的关系
frames to everything in the robot's environment and write down the relationships between the
坐标框架。这是一种非常严格的方法，最终会为您节省很多
coordinate frames. It’s a very rigorous approach and will ultimately save you a lot
时间不要害怕使用大量的坐标框架。
of time. Don't be afraid to use lots of coordinate frames.
坐标框架遵循右手惯例，X轴和Y轴
Coordinate frames follow the right-handed convention, the X axis and the Y axis are
像这样相关。如果我们有2个坐标框架，它们之间的相对旋转
related like this. If we have 2 coordinate frames the relative rotation between them
如此定义，角度在逆时针方向上正向增加。积分可以
is defined like this, angle increases positively in the anti-clockwise direction. Points can
表示为关于特定坐标框架的矢量和我们的符号
be represented as vectors with respect to particular coordinate frames and in our notation
我们用小写p表示一个向量，前面的标签表示该向量
we denote a vector by lower case p, and the preceding label indicates the frame that the
向量是关于，并且尾随标签指示该向量的目的地。
vector is with respect to, and the trailing label indicates the destination of that vector.
因此，在这种情况下，A表示向量从帧A的原点开始的事实
So in this case the A denotes the fact that the vector starts at the origin of frame A
它到了B点。
and it goes to the point B.
我们可以用姿势来描述两个坐标系之间的关系。并摆出姿势
We can describe the relationship between two coordinate frames in terms of pose. And pose
是有三个参数的东西：它有一个翻译，X和Y组件
is something that has got three parameters: it's got a translation, the X and Y component
和旋转是theta组件。我们可以将它视为一个简单的动作，一个翻译
and the rotation which is the theta component. We can consider it as a simple motion, a translation
和一个轮换。在图形上，我们用具有三角形头部的粗矢量表示姿势。
and a rotation. Graphically we denote pose by a thick vector with a triangular head.
象征性地，我们用希腊字母ksi来表示它。左侧标签表示
Symbolically we represent it by the Greek letter ksi. The left-hand label indicates
参照系和右手标签表示目的地姿势。所以
the frame of reference and the right-hand label indicates the destination pose. So in
这种情况说这是从坐标系A到坐标系B的相对姿势。
this case this is saying this is the relative pose from coordinate frame A to coordinate frame B.
我们可以根据不同坐标系的矢量描述一个点。
We can describe a point in terms of vectors with respect to different coordinate frames.
在这种情况下，点D，我们可以用附加坐标框架C中的向量来描述
In this case the point D, we can describe with a vector in coordinate frame C attached
到世界各地固定的汽车或坐标框架W.我们可以改造一个
to the car or coordinate frame W which is fixed within the world. We can transform a
通过应用点运算符和姿势从一个坐标框架到另一个坐标框架，
vector from one coordinate frame to another by applying the dot operator and the pose,
它描述了两个坐标系之间的关系。我们不能简单地添加
which describes the relationship between the two coordinate frames. We can't simply add
矢量和姿势，因为它们是不同的数学对象。
vectors and poses because they are different mathematical objects.
我们可以结合姿势。因此，如果我们知道从A帧到B帧的姿势和来自的姿势
We can combine poses. So if we know the pose from frame A to frame B and the pose from
帧B到帧C然后我们使用O+运算符将它们组成相对姿势
frame B to frame C then we use the O+ operator to compose them into the relative pose from
框架A到框架C，我们可以无限期地扩展这种方法。有时这个过程
frame A to frame C, and we can extend this approach indefinitely. This process is sometimes
称为复合或组合。
called compounding or composition.
我们可以重写一组复杂的空间关系，这些空间关系是根据坐标框架定义的
We can rewrite a complex set of spatial relationships defined in terms of coordinate frames, in
有点整洁，姿势图。我们可以使用姿势图来编写空间
terms of a bit tidier, a pose graph. And we can use the pose graph to write spatial
根据其他相对姿势描述相对姿势的关系。
relationships that describe relative poses in terms of other relative poses.
我们引入了空间代数。需要注意的重要事项是我们可以撰写或
We introduced a spatial algebra. The important things to note are that we can compose or
使用O+运算符复合两个相对姿势。O+运算符不是可交换的，所以ksi
compound two relative poses using the O+ operator. The O+ operator is not commutative so ksi
1O+ksi2不等于ksi2O+ksi1。
1 O+ ksi 2 is not equal to ksi 2 O+ ksi 1.
我们有一个零姿势的概念，它是零相对运动。如果我们添加它或我们减去
We have a concept of a null pose that's a zero relative motion. If we add it or we subtract
它从一个姿势没有区别，原始姿势没有变化。我们介绍了
it from a pose it makes no difference, the original pose is unchanged. And we introduced
否定算子，O-符号，相当于Xksi的反向运动
a negation operator, the O- symbol, and that is equivalent to the inverse motion of X ksi
Y，从帧X到帧Y的运动，否则是从帧Y到帧X的运动。
Y, the motion from frame X to frame Y, the negation of that is motion from frame Y to frame X.
我们还引入了点运算符，它将矢量从一个坐标系转换为另一个坐标系。
And we also introduced the dot operator which transforms a vector from one coordinate frame to another.
这些都是非常抽象的概念。我们已经介绍了很多符号
These are all very abstract concepts. We've introduced a lot of symbols, we've introduced
ksi表示姿势，O+，O-和点。
ksi to represent a pose, O+, O- and the dot.
下一步是将其转化为真正的数学对象，我们可以用术语来描述旋转
The next step is to turn this into real mathematical objects and we can describe rotation in terms
2x2矩阵，用于将矢量从一个坐标系转换为另一个坐标
of a 2 x 2 matrix that transforms a vector from one coordinate frame to another coordinate
如果这两个帧的起源相同，则为frame。2x2旋转矩阵是
frame if the origins of those two frames are identical. The 2 x 2 rotation matrix is an
正交或正交矩阵，其逆与其转置及其行列式相同
orthogonal or orthonormal matrix, its inverse is the same as its transpose and its determinant
总是+1。我们说这样的矩阵属于维度的特殊正交群
is always +1. We say that such matrices belong to the special orthogonal group of dimension
2.矩阵将矢量从坐标系B变换到坐标系A，但是它被定义
2. The matrix transforms a vector from coordinate frame B to coordinate frame A, but it is defined
就坐标框架A与坐标框架B的角度而言。
in terms of the angle from coordinate frame A to coordinate frame B.
最后，我们可以用具体的数学对象来描述姿势，这是一个
Finally we can describe pose in terms of a concrete mathematical object and that is a
3x3齐次变换矩阵属于特殊欧几里德群
3 x 3 homogeneous transformation matrix which belongs to the special Euclidean group of
尺寸2.均匀变换矩阵包含旋转矩阵和它
dimension 2. The homogeneous transformation matrix contains the rotation matrix and it
还包含翻译-这是从原始帧A到原点的向量
also contains the translation - that's the vector from the origin frame A to the origin
因此，这种齐次变换矩阵等价于抽象符号
of frame B. So this homogeneous transformation matrix is equivalent to the abstract symbol
我们之前用过的ksi。点用矢量来描述，但是当我们使用齐次时
ksi that we've used earlier. Points are described in terms of vectors, but when we use the homogeneous
转换，我们用均匀向量描述点。我们拿原件
transformation, we describe points in terms of homogeneous vectors. We take the original
矢量与两个元素，我们追加一个元素。
vector with two elements and we append a one element to that.
我们介绍抽象O+算子的姿势的组成由矩阵执行
Composition of poses for which we introduce the abstract O+ operator is performed by matrix
乘法。我们将两个3x3矩阵相乘，得到一个新的3x3矩阵。
multiplication. We multiply the two 3 x 3 matrices together to yield a new 3 x 3 matrix.
我们之前由O-算子抽象描述的否定是反过来的
Negation which we described previously by the abstract by the O- operator is the inverse
同构变换矩阵，并记住一个齐次的逆
of the homogeneous transformation matrix, and remember that the inverse for a homogeneous
矩阵不等于它的转置。该属性仅属于旋转矩阵
matrix is not equal to its transpose. That property only belongs to a rotation matrix
这只是齐次变换矩阵的一小部分。
which is just a little part of the homogeneous transform matrix.
我们用来从一个坐标系变换矢量的抽象运算符点
The abstract operator dot which we used to transform a vector from one coordinate frame
通过将齐次变换矩阵乘以齐次来实现另一个
to another is implemented by multiplying the homogeneous transformation matrix by the homogeneous
该向量的表示。
representation of that vector.